If you're working with data,
إذا كنتم تتعامل مع البيانات،
you can always build a Quick Plot to see the shape.
فيمكنكم دائمًا إنشاء مخطط سريع للاطلاع على الشكل.
Just to apply some context,
ولتطبيق بعض السياقات،
some examples of approximately Bell-Shaped data include heights and weights,
تتضمن بعض الأمثلة على بيانات Bell-Shaped تقريبًا الارتفاعات والأوزان،
standardized test scores, precipitation amounts,
أو درجات الاختبار الموحد، أو كميات هطول الأمطار،
the mean of a distribution,
أو متوسط التوزيع،
or errors in manufacturing processes.
أو أخطاء عمليات التصنيع.
Common data that follow Left Skewed Distributions include GPAs,
وتشتمل البيانات المشتركة التي تتبع Left Skewed Distributions على GPAs،
the age of death,
وعمر الوفاة،
and asset price changes.
والتغيرات في أسعار الأصول.
Common data that follow approximately
وتشتمل البيانات الشائعة التي تتبع
Right Skewed Distributions include the amount of drug left in your bloodstream over time,
Right Skewed Distributionsتقريبًا على مقدار الدواء المتبقي في مجرى الدم مع مرور الوقت،
the distribution of wealth,
وتوزيع الثروة،
and human athletic abilities.
والقدرات الرياضية البشرية.
There are links below in
وفيما يلي روابط في
the instructor notes in case you want to learn more about each of these cases.
ملاحظات المعلم إذا كنتم تريدون معرفة المزيد عن كل من هذه الحالات.
Though these three, Right Skewed,
على الرغم من أن هؤلاء الثلاثة، "Right Skewed"،
Left Skewed and Symmetric,
"Left Skewed" و"Symmetric"،
are the most common distributions,
هي التوزيعات الأكثر شيوعًا،
data in the real world can be messy and it might not follow any of these distributions.
إلا البيانات في العالم الحقيقي قد تكون فوضوية ولا تتبع أيًا من هذه التوزيعات.
We will talk about this more in the next section.
سنتحدث عن هذا بتوسع في القسم التالي.